Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Records ALBA.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: General Files, 1940-2006
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1990-2003 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Cards and Notes, undated, 1970-1995 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Detentions, British embassy, 1942-1947 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1939-1950 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: New York Public Library, Donated Materials, 1948-1950 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Spanish Government, 1965-1978 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: United Nations, 1946-1951 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: United States Congress, 1943-1947, 1960, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: United States Department of State, 1943-1975 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: United States Post Office, 1939-1950, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: United States President, 1941-1978 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: Union General de Trabajadores de Espana (UGT), 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Cullinen, George, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Cuba, 1948, 1976-1977, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum and Courses, undated, 1975-1979, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum and Courses: Proposal for a Center for Spanish Civil War Studies, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Czech and Slovak Anti-Fascist Fighters Associations, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - DeMaio, Anthony, undated, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Democratic Socialists of America, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - De Vries, Lini: "Farewell U.S.A." in La Palabra y el Hombre, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Diamant, David: Jewish Volunteers, 1955, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Dorland, Norman, undated, 1942-1946 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Doyle, Bob: Memoir, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Dua-Bogen, Gershon: Quest for Power, translation, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Eby, Cecil: Between the Bullet and the Lie(review and correspondence), undated, 1970-1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Echeverria, Carlos Sule, 1950-1954 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Egg-Benes, Maria, undated, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Erceg, Michael: Parole, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Exhibits, undated, 1992, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Exhibits: Drew University, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Exhibits: Posters, Spanish Civil War, 1942-1944 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Exhibits: "Shouts From the Wall," Hamilton College, undated, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Ephemera: Stamps, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Films, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Films: "Comrades" Film, List of Photographs for, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Films: The Good Fight, undated, 1978-1984 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Films: The Good Fight, Controversy, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Financial: Budgets, 1940, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Financial: Certificate of Authority for Unincorporated Association Account, 1947-1953 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Financial: Correspondence, undated, 1947-1949 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Financial: Invoices, miscellaneous, 1951-1976, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Financial: Ledger and General Journal, 1949-1953 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Financial: Payroll Books, 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Financial: Reports, 1940-1949 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Financial: Reports, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Financial: Reports, 1971-1984 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Fisher, Harry: Comrades: Tales of a Brigadista in the Spanish Civil War, Correspondence and Reviews, undated, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1971-2001 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Friedman, Jack: Correspondence, 1944-1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Gallagher, Joe: Memoir, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Gandall, William, 1946-1987 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Gandall, William: Memoir, undated, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Geiser, Carl, undated, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - German Democratic Republic, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Goldring, Ben, 1959-1980 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Harris, Albert, 1949, 1952, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Historical Commission, undated, 1968-1982 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Historical Commission: Correspondence, undated, 1975-1981 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Historical Commission: Moscow Archives, 1976-1979 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC), 1963 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - HUAC: American Committee for the Defense of the Foreign Born, undated, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - HUAC: Committee for Democratic Rights in the U.S.A., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - HUAC: Civil Liberties, Slide Show--transcript, ca.1955 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - HUAC: Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties, Speeches, 1962, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - HUAC: Civil Rights Congress, undated, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - HUAC: Cohen, Milton, 1965-1969 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - HUAC: Committee to Abolish, 1966, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - HUAC: Committee to Defend Lincoln Veterans, Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - HUAC: Committee to Defend Lincoln Veterans, Rally, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - HUAC: Committee to Defend Lincoln Veterans, Women's Committee, undated, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - HUAC: Committee to End Sedition Laws, undated, 1953-1956 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - HUAC: Defense Committees, undated, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - HUAC: Emergency Civil Liberties Committees, 1962-1965, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - HUAC: Fishman, Moe, subpoena, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - HUAC: Friends of Pete Seeger, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - HUAC: Sid, Linn, organizing, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - HUAC: Mc Neil, Allan D. (Allan Johnson), undated, 1952-1966 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - HUAC: New York Civil Rights Congress, 1951-1953 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - HUAC: Pittsburgh Civil Rights Congress, 1952-1955 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - HUAC: Pittsburgh Trial, Committee to Defend Lincoln Veterans, undated, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - HUAC: Pittsburgh Trial, Correspondence--Steve Nelson, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - HUAC: Pittsburgh Trial, Defense Committee, undated, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - HUAC: Pittsburgh Trial, Legal Documents, undated, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - HUAC: Pittsburgh Trial, Petition, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - HUAC: Smith Act, 1949, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - HUAC: Smith Act: "The Case of Martha Stone", undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - HUAC: Subversive Activities Control Board, undated, 1955, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - HUAC: Walter-McCarran Act, Frank Bonetti, undated, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - HUAC: Walter-Mc Carran Act, Peggy Wellman Defense Committee, undated, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Hutchins, Evelyn, 1977, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Hyde, Mark Powell (Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran and executive secretary of the Washington, D.C. Chapter of the United American Spanish Aid Committee) Letters to Sam and Fredericka Barenberg (later Fredericka Martin) (also includes one reply from Sam Barenberg), circa 1944-1946 (Box 17, Folder 1a)
  - Ilitch, General Ljubomir, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - International Brigade Association (UK), 1950-2001 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - International Brigade Memorial Trust (UK), 2004-2005 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - International Brigades, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - International Brigades: 35th Anglo-American Battery, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - International Brigades: Amicale des Anciens Volontaires de l' Espagne Republicaine, 1956, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - International Brigades: Asociación Brigadas Internacionales, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - International Brigades: Australian Veterans, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - International Brigades: Botwin Veterans (Poland), undated, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - International Brigades: Clippings, undated, 1996-1999 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - International Brigades: La Comision de Homenaje, undated, 1980, 1994-1999 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - International Brigades: Committee of Social Help, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - International Brigades: Conference, report, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - International Brigades: Czechoslovakian Veterans, 1990, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - International Brigades: Italian Volunteers, undated (Box 17, Folder 15a)
  - International Brigades: MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, 1972-2004 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - International Brigades: MacKenzie-Papineau Batallion, News Bulletin, 1976-1995 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - International Brigades: Poland, Veterans' Benefits, undated, 1970-1972, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - International Brigades: Reunion, 40th-Florence, Italy, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - International Brigades: Spanish Citizenship, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - International Brigades: Sociedad Francisco Javier Mina, Mexico, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - International Brigades: Soviet Veterans, undated, 1975-1977, 1985-1988 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - International Brigades: Veterans' Food Packages, Europe, ca.1946-1948 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - International Front against Torture, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Kee, Salaria (a.k.a. Salaria Kea) by James Yates, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Kish, Leslie: Memoir, Dispute, undated, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Kramer, Jacob, 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Kranes, Louis, 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Landis, Arthur, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Landis, Arthur: Spain! The Unfinished Revolution, correspondence, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Landis, Arthur: "The United States of America and the Cause of the Spanish Republic," draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Lawsuit: VALB v. Eric Bernay et al., 1947 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Lending, Ed, 1993-1999 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Lists: 711 Group of the 95th Street Food Conspiracy, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Lists: Fellows and Sponsors, Potential, undated (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Lists: Mailing, undated, 1951, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Lists: Mailing, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Lists: Mailing, undated (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Lists: Mailing, International, undated, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Lists: Mailing Labels, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Lists: Photographs, undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Lists: Veterans, undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Lists: VALB, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Lustgarten, Larry, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Martin, Fredericka, undated (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Martin, Fredericka: Correspondence, 1970-1986 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Maki, Martin, 1973-1980 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Matson, Eric: Foster Care of Eric, Jr., 1948 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Mayer, Pablo, undated, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - McCarthy, Bill, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Medem, Gina: "Roofs of New York" (excerpt, translation), undated (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Mexico, 1944, 1961, ca.1963 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Middle East, undated, 1970, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Middle East: Gulf War, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Miller, Israel Jack, v. the United States: Bail, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Mooney, Tom, 1938, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - National Board, 1939-1948 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - National Board, 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - National Board, 1970-1975 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - National Board, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - National Board, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - National Board, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - National Board, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - National Board, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - National Board, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - National Board, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - National Board, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - National Board, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - National Board, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - National Board, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - National Board: Administrative Committee, 1977-1981 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - National Board: Executive, 1972-1990 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - National Board: Executive, Minutes, 1942-1947 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - National Board: "Minutes Charter Constitution Finances", 1939-1941 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - National Board: Resident, Minutes, 1973-1977 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1972, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Negrin, Juan, undated, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Nelson, Cary: Madrid 1937, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Nelson, Cary: Madrid 1937, script, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Nelson, Cary: Essay on Edwin Rolfe, undated, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Nelson, Steve, undated, 1953-1956, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Neugass, James: "They Will Come Back", undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Nicaragua, undated, 1985-1991 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - North, Joe: "A Strange American Story," draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - O' Casey, Sean, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - O' Casey, Sean: Correspondence, 1957, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Office File, undated, 1941-1948 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Office File: Certificates of Incorporation, 1939-1954 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Parker, Dorothy: Appeal, Dec 27, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Parker, Max: Al Tosca Diana: Songs From a Franco Prison, undated, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Passports: Correspondence, 1937-1944, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Poland, undated, 1977, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Posts: Bay Area, 1937-2001 (Box 29, Folder 1-14, Box MSOS 007, Folder 1)
  - Posts: Bay Area, undated, 1952-1956, 1974-2000 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Posts: Bay Area, Anniversaries, 1982-2003 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Posts: Bay Area, Correspondence, undated, 1949-1978 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Posts: Bay Area, "Postscript to a War: Voices of the Lincoln Brigade", 1995 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Posts: Chicago, undated; 1941-1952 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Posts: Chicago, 1995-2003 (Box 27, Box 28)
  - Posts: Chicago Friends of the Lincoln Brigade, undated, 1998-2000 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Posts: Los Angeles, undated; 1952-1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Posts: New York, undated, 1972-1985 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Posts: New York, Permits and Licenses, 1940-1951 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Posts: Pennsylvania, Delaware Valley, 1975-1979 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Posts: South Florida, undated, 1976-1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1940-1949 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1950-1956 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, undated, 1960-1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases: "Statesments" [sic], 1919-1941 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Bulletin, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Publications: No Pasaran!, Spanien Kaempfer, 2004-2006 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Servicio de Prensa, Jun 1973-Nov 1973 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Publications: Volunteer for Liberty, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Publications: Volunteer for Liberty, Orders, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Publications: Volunteer for Liberty, Orders--Colleges, 1949-1952 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Publications: Volunteer for Liberty, Orders--Public Libraries, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Puerto Rico: Vieques, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Ragner, Albin C., undated, 1982, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Rauschwald, Mark, 1963-1971 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Raven, Bob: Rehabilitation, 1942-1949 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Reed, Bob, undated, 1977-1999 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Reunion: Spain, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Reunion: Spain, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Reunion: Spain, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Reunion: Spain, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Reunion: Spain: Clippings, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Reunion: Spain: Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Rodriquez, Julius: National Desertion Bureau, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Rolfe, Edwin: The Lincoln Battalion, German Translation, undated (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor: Correspondence, 1943, 1951, 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Ryan, Frank, 1944, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Ryan, William G.: "I Fought in Spain," in Scribner's Commentator, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Sanchez, Pablo Guaelpo, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Sender, Andrea (Sister Benedicta), undated, 1982-1984 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Sarbaugh, Thomas: Spanish Civil War Music, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Sennett, Bill, 1972-1997 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Shirai, Jack, undated, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete), 1977-1980 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete): Communist Party, Controversy, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete): Interview, Transcript, undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Sossenko, George, 1988, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Spain: Agencia de Prensa Espana Popular (APER), Newsletter, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Spain: Articles and Reports, 1940s (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Spain: Articles and Reports, 1960s (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Spain: Articles and Reports, 1970s (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Spain: Articles and Reports, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Spain: Articles and Reports, Informaciones y Documentacion sobre Espana, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Spain: Asociacion de Ex-Presos y Represaliados Politicos, 1980-1985 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Spain: Basque, undated, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Spain: Catalonia, politics and protest, undated, 1976-1990 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1942-1959 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Spain: Clippings, undated, 1966-1995 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Spain: Comite d' Information et de Solidarite avec l' Espagne (C.I.S.E.), undated, 1973, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Spain: Committee for a Democratic Alternative in Aragon, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Spain: Communism, Clippings, undated, 1960-1984 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Spain: Communist Party (P.C.E.), undated, 1971-1975, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Spain: Des Amis de l' Espagne Republicaine, 1952, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Spain: Dissident Groups, undated, 1960-1967 (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Spain: Elections, 1976-1977, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Spain: Friends of National Spain, "Exposure of the Secret Plan to Establish a Soviet in Spain", undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Spain: Gobierno Republica Espanola, Paris, undated, 1962-1963 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Spain: Guerrillas, undated, 1941, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Spain: Labor Unrest, ca.1965-1975 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Spain: "The People's Front," Outline, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Spain: People's Socialist Party (P.S.P.), Bulletin, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, undated, 1971-1976 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Ana, Marcos, 1964-1971 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Des Anciens Internes Politiques et Resistants--Bulletin, 1976-1981 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Carabanchel 10, undated, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Children's Vacation Fund, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Clippings, undated, 1952-1974 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Comision Ejecutiva Permante Latino Americana, 1960-1961 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Commissie hulp aan Spanje, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conference, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conference, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conferences, undated, 1953-1965 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Conferences--Latin America, undated, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Correspondence, undated, 1948, 19591960 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Correspondence--Appeals, undated, 1959, 19711974 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Defense Fund--Booklet, undated (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Duchess of Medina-Sidonia, 1968, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Grimau, Julian, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, International Committee of the Comisiones de Solidaridad de Catalunya, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, O'Casey, Sean, undated, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Pena, Leoncio, 1959-1964 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Prison--Oviedo, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Reports and Statements, undated, 1954-1963, 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, Speech-Pete Smith, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Spain: Political Prisoners, United Nations--Appeal, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Spain: Politics, notebook, undated (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Spain: Publications, Spanish Newsletter, Feb 1972-Oct 1972 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Spain: Protests, Nov 1976 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Spain: Students, undated, 1952, 1967-1976 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Spain: "Twenty-Five Years of Military Involvement", 1975 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Spain: United Furniture Workers of America, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Spain: Women, Union de Mujeres Espanolas, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Spain: Workers' Commission, 1973-1976 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Spain: Spanish-American Defense Committee, undated (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Spanish Civil War, American Writing and the: Richard Bjornson, undated, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Spanish Civil War: "Americanos en el Hospital de las Brigadas Internacionales de Benicassam", 1997 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Spanish Civil War: Bibliographies, undated, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Spanish Civil War: Bibliography, articles (1937-1954), undated (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Spanish Civil War: Collectors' Catalogues, undated, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Spanish Civil War: Death Benefit Claims, Correspondence, 1939, 1942-1949 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Spanish Civil War: Ebro, Battle of--Map, undated (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Spanish Civil War: Fuerte de Carchuna, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Spanish Civil War: Irish and Irish-Americans, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Civil War: Jewish Volunteers, undated, 1966, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Ambulance Drivers, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, American participants, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Missing, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Mortality, undated, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Mortality (Canadian Volunteers), 1974 (Box 21, Folder 9A)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Prisoners, undated, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Sailing, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Sailing (return), undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Spanish Civil War: Lists, Veterans, undated, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Civil War: Manuscript, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Spanish Civil War: Memoirs, Drafts, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Civil War: " Postscript in Blood", undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners, German, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners of War, "Diplomatic Protection", undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners of War, Manuscript I, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Spanish Civil War: Prisoners of War, Manuscript II, undated (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Spanish Civil War: Recruitment, book chapter, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Spanish Civil War: Research File, articles, undated, 1937-1940, 1962-1969 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Spanish Civil War: Songs, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Spanish Civil War: Songs, The Songs of the Lincoln Brigade--Correspondence, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Spanish Civil War: Union de Excombatientes de la Guerra de Espana, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Spanish Civil War: "A View from a Midwest Campus," by Robert Perlman (typescript, with original SCW button), 1982 (Box 21, Folder 26)